[Music]
[Applause]
training
so i've always been a huge advocate of
bodyweight training at the very least if
you know how to get a good workout then
you always have a place to train you
know no matter where you go you can
always work your muscles hard
now some muscles are easier to train
with body weight than others mainly the
pushing muscles
they're easy to train with body weight
because you just need your body and a
floor
you know you can do handstand stuff you
can do
push-ups from different angles and you
can do even dips so you can do all these
pressing movements and you can do all
these squatting movements to work your
quads you know
different squats lunges step ups split
squats
so quads pecs you know triceps front
delts and
to some extent the glutes are very easy
to train now some muscles are hard to
train with body weight mainly the
pulling muscles you need something to
grip on to
so if you have a chin up bar that's
great you can train your lats uh
and you know you can do uh inverted rows
and stuff like that if you have
something to grip on to and with
hamstrings
you almost need like something to do
nordic ham curls or something to trap
you in to do like back extensions
nevertheless since the glutes have three
joint actions you know hip extension
hip back snore rotation hip abduction
there's a wide variety of exercises for
the glutes and there's also a lot of
ways to progress in exercise and make it
harder
so obviously training from home has
become much more important
in this era because of the quarantine
you know because of kovid
i have friends that didn't go to gym for
an entire year so
hopefully you can acquire dumbbells and
bands if you have dumbbells and bands it
makes things so much easier
because now you can add weight to your
lunges and your squats and your
hip thrusts and things like that but
even if you just had your own body
weight as long as you have different
types of furniture around the house i
truly believe that you can
either build your glutes if you're you
know
a novice or intermediate or at least
maintain your glutes
if you're advanced the trick is to know
the right exercise to perform
so i have broken down the home glute
exercise into three categories
ones that are best suited for novices
you know beginners the ones that are
kind of intermediate and then you have
the advanced glute exercises but i do
want it to be known that even if you're
advanced you can still do the exercises
in the previous two categories you'll
just do them with higher reps now let's
say you start with these exercises in
this video
and with just body weight and then over
time you acquire
some dumbbells of different sizes you
acquire ankle weights
you buy a bunch of glute loops in that
case you will have it vastly
improve the likelihood of building your
glutes because now you can add load
but even take a guy like myself you know
i've been training for
almost 30 years now i've hip-thrusted
800 pounds
i've deadlifted 635 pounds and a few
times a week i still do my frog pumps
and my lateral band walks and that
workout you know the frog pumps
annihilate my lower glutes and the
lateral bandwalks
annihilate my upper glutes and i have
the craziest pump so i
feel that workout a lot more than i do
my heavy workout but i think they're
synergistic you know the heavyweight
which you do with progressive overload
in mind and then the bodyweight and band
stuff which is performed more with a
mind muscle connection and for the pump
but rest assured if you master the
exercise in this video and you go on to
be a rock star in the advanced column
you're gonna build some booty or you're
at least gonna maintain what you already
have so i was very happy to have my
friend grace chen visiting me
and here are the home glute exercises
broken down in a novice intermediate and
advanced
welcome to casa de contreras uh
in this video i'm going to show you how
to train glutes from home
but i'm going to break it down into
novice exercises
intermediate exercise and advanced
exercise so i am
lucky to have grace chen with me aka
young grace she's going to demonstrate
these exercises for me so we're just
going to roll through them
the first glute exercise to do at home
is the standard glute bridge
so lay down
palms flat all right just bust out five
reps of
every exercise one two we're looking for
around a right a right angle at the
knees at the top
she doesn't want to hyperextend too much
show a hyper
over hyperextension too much you don't
want to go that far okay
that's the glute bridge now scoot
forward you can do the feet elevated
glute bridge
and that i would recommend pushing
through the corner not
heels if you push through the heels at
the top then it's more hamstring
okay five reps go for it one
now this just has a little more range of
motion but
due to the angle it's a little bit
easier it's a little bit less quad a
little bit more hammy
okay so that's the feet elevated glute
bridge now flip around let's show them
the hip thrust
okay
five reps
okay one two
three pushing through the heels right
angle at the knees
reaching full hip extension looking
forward okay
so that's the hip thrust now we're going
to the b stance hip thrust and this
is a variation where you want to kind of
put around 70
of the load on the switch legs do it
yeah so you want about
70 percent load on this leg and then put
lift this uh toe up yep
so this toe actually put it like there
just a little closer okay it's mostly a
single leg extra it's a it's a
quasi or like a pseudo single leg
exercise because you're using both but
you're using what much more of one than
the other so try to focus on this leg
doing the work
go for it okay
okay so that's the b stance hip thrust
again
most of the work is being done by the
right leg though then she'd switch legs
and match the number of reps
all right stand up let me help you up oh
thank you
let's do a box squat now we can do a
high box squat like
you could if you're depending how out of
shape you are
you can kind of what i like is to stand
diagonal with there
yep yep
come all the way down cross your arms
yep
so everyone starts somewhere
the easiest of squats is the box squat
and then once you get better you can do
a lower box squat
okay use this
sure
okay you could go low like this
and then in addition to doing
box squats you can just do free squats
okay
and put your hands forward yep
this is the easiest way so box squats
and squats
are beginner movements for
actually you know if you're obese a lot
of these exercises are
just good exercise they get your heart
rate going they're very challenging
if i train obese subjects i might give
them you know three sets of 20 glute
bridges three sets of 20 box squats
it whoops their butt so uh
and then some of these exercises can
also be done by advanced like i do
squats just bodyweight squats i'll do
three sets of 30
constant tension style i'll go over that
so some of them have some crossover but
in general these are the easiest ones
easiest ones so now we're going to show
a split squat so
now we're moving into more single leg
not a bulgarian split squat you're just
going to
stand on the ground yep okay
there you go so this is the split squat
you're putting around eighty percent of
your loading on the front foot
twenty percent on the rear foot all
right
now we have the low step up okay so
again everyone starts somewhere i've
trained people this is where they
started
in fact um i've
trained people where i had to hold on to
their hands like this while they do it
okay and this was where they started and
then i gradually moved the
increase the range of motion over time
all right and then then eventually i
take my
you know keep going i take my assistance
away or they could
brace onto something they could do it
near a wall where they can kind of use
for balance
and then the goal is to increase the
height over time all right now we got
the reaching
romanian deadlift okay so you're gonna
do you know the
that whole thing go for it okay
reach up higher as you come up but be as
fluid so where you're yep and then hold
on
come down so you're gonna be like right
here but look
look down can you go deeper there
there's where you want to be at the
bottom
okay go for it well
this is uh she just whispered this is
beginner
because it's hard for but it's hard for
because of balance this is hard for me
i always feel like i'm drunk or
something when i do these i'm so off
balance but it's a balance exercise it's
not really a strength training exercise
it's not hard for any of the muscles
now we have this spread eagle reverse
hyper so
you can find either a countertop or you
can find you can do them over a couch or
something
we're gonna show over the counter top
i don't know let's see yeah you're gonna
be fine
okay so this is the spread eagle reverse
hyper
and you can see she starts narrow ends
wide
okay now what if you're on like a couch
or a lower
table then you're going to do the bent
to straight leg reverse hyper so you
start out bent
and then you kick back there bent to
straight leg
thing you want to watch out for here is
don't overarch here
try to move mostly through the hips okay
thank you
moving on
we're going to get on all fours and do
the quadruped hip extension
so grace is going to get on all fours
she's going to keep looking up
straight back kick back yep straight
back
not like straight leg bent the whole
time yep
perfect five reps
she's not overarching here see how this
remains stable okay then she would
switch
and repeat on the other leg
now another option is the back extension
so what grace is going to do here is
just kind of
she's going to drape herself over this
and i'm gonna hold her legs now
obviously you need a partner for this
but it's real easy like i can do this
with one hand watch
it's very easy to hold here okay
so it's not hard if you had a kid you
could almost have a kid hold your legs
here okay
so that's the back extension
now we have a few exercises left we're
getting in side lying position
we have this sideline clam
so from here you're just going to get
kind of criss-cross your feet right
there and then
come up but don't lean back stay forward
there come as high as you can there this
is the sideline clam
when you do it right there's not that
much range of motion
okay now from here she's going to
straighten
she can either straighten her legs or
this leg can be bent
now she's going to make sure she's in
the frontal plane her body is straight
so i would say there
now she's going to put this foot down
into internal rotation
and she's going to come up okay so this
is the sideline hip abduction
okay now
back to quadruped you're gonna do a fire
hydrant
this is called a fire hunter because it
looks like you're a dog peeing on the
fire hydrant
and again you don't twist too much she
could rotate and come way up like that
but the goal is to just mostly stay
neutral that you can't come up as high
good okay that's the fire hydrant
finally we have one last exercise stand
up
and grace is gonna do a standing glute
squeeze so from here
[Applause]
you want to be in a posterior pelvic
tilt this is
if you do it right your butt looks ugly
you get ugly butt post your pelvic tilt
butt okay
shoulder show arch now arch real quick
arch this was like if you're taking a
picture someone's taking a picture of
your butt and now show this
glue squeeze see how it tucks under and
a poster pelvic tilt
okay show says your hip dips
so you would do that for about ten
second holds maybe like four sets of ten
and those are your beginner glute
exercises
all right back for round two now we're
gonna go over our
intermediate glute exercises so we're
gonna start off with the
frog pump grace is gonna get on the
ground
and she's gonna yep
push through the elbows the feet now the
he she's gonna push through the heels i
like the toes away from each other
okay go for it now note here her heels
are close to her butt they're not far
away
also note she's doing this correctly you
some people love frog
pumps some people don't so there's about
two thirds of people like them one third
that don't
now if she comes all the way down to
here
do a few reps do you not like those
she doesn't like it feels weird so she
comes up a little bit
so toy around with that with
with your you know hip abduction level
and figure out the right one for you now
if you don't feel these and you don't
they don't feel right um
don't worry about it i do these these
are actually frog pumps are my favorite
glute exercise
i do body weight but i'll do you know
i'll do
three sets of 80 or i'll do like 120
180 or you know 100 120
80 and 60 or something like that i
always keep them even numbers but i do
these all the time i do these several
times a week with just body weight
all right now we're going to do single
leg hip thrust
okay so flip around
all right grace is going to put her arms
out
come up with two legs now put your feet
together
drive the heels back just a little bit
okay pick one leg up pick this let's do
the other let's show the other one
keep it right here the whole time okay
come down
come up now notice on this
grace doesn't keep her gaze for she
doesn't keep her gaze forward and move
mostly from the sternum down like we do
show that she doesn't do it like this
this doesn't feel right huh
she does this hingey so she pushes as
tall as she can
tap the ground come up okay then you
would
switch legs match reps with the other
side we don't need to show that okay
now flip around let's show this single
leg
uh foot elevated glute bridge okay
so this you're doing one leg at a time
yep okay and this is a great
glute exercise a lot of people love this
okay
now we're gonna show the constant
tension
squat okay so this is just you're gonna
do it
put your arms out you're just gonna do
squats but you're gonna do them kind of
rapidly
go for it no deep deep yep there
good now i do these
three sets of 30 and i rest about
one minute in between sets and these
kill me these smoke my quads but i do
feel them in my glutes when i do these
so you got it but the trick is doing
constant tension style like that
and that's a pretty good glute exercise
if you have no equipment
now next up we've got the medium step up
so we're going to go from right here
foot on the table okay
hands on hips or you could do them in
front of you either way
go for it good so again we just
increase the height of the step
all right now we're going to show the
bulgarian split squat so come back here
put your
back foot there you go
okay these bulgarians are a legendary
single leg movement these are hard
i don't care who you are 20 bulgarian
split squads is tough
okay all right we also have the reverse
lunge so move forward and just take a
step back
good alternate okay
i like doing these alternating style and
then
this is very similar to the walking
lunge so let's start back here
okay
yep i want you to show kind of keep your
body
oriented forward but when you step kind
of step out a little bit zigzag just a
little bit
good but don't aim that way
keep your bodies free yeah there that's
how i like to do these
okay and you can do these you know
i used to give my clients my even my
more advanced clients i'd go go out to
the parking lot
do a hundred walking lunges so 50 each
leg
and that's pretty brutal so don't
underestimate that now we also have the
curtsy lunge
so grace is going to just kind of step
back
into a stretch he's going to get this
stretch
perfect
switch legs okay
now notice she's just trying to get a
little extra stretch here so she kind of
comes backwards at an angle all right
that's the curtsy lunge
now we have the assisted pistol squat
so you need to have someone
your leg's going to go straight yeah
okay
and she's going to use me for assistance
all right
now this is not for everyone not every
intermediate can do this
but over time like let's say she was
really weak she could just use me a lot
you know she could just pull a lot on me
and then over time
i'm hoping she uses me less and less and
you can kind of gauge that of course you
need a partner for that unless you have
some object like in the gym we do it
in the power rack we put a barbell out
and they can put the barbell about right
here and then they can hold on or you
can use them with
like uh like trx or suspension straps
but i'm sure you could mimic something
in the house you could use like a long
towel
trapped in a doorway or something all
right
now we've got the back extension but
she's going to put
her hands behind her head in the
prisoner position so
i'm going to hold on to her feet
yep so put your yup like that go for it
this makes it a little bit harder
nope this one you're not rounding
straight up
yep okay so this one she doesn't round
so this is a good glute exercise you
actually feel this in the hammies
the erectors and the glutes okay good
all right sorry
[Music]
you go flipping forward okay um
so that's the prisoner back extension
now we've got the quadruped leg swing
okay
what i want
young grace to do let's put your
knee on this okay you're gonna face
this way but put your right knee on that
yep and put your hands there now
good okay you're gonna kind of keep just
a very slight bend in this knee
and then come kick back and then you
come way
forward don't bend it so much about here
to there okay go for it
yep perfect
now i do these for sets of 30 and i'll
do them a little faster
and i will i'll actually feel this in my
glute it's a body weight
you know kickback movement and i feel it
good okay now
we've got the frog reverse hyper
now grace is going to come up here on
the table
now this one she puts her
heels together now she's not pushing
through her toes at all though
she's just pushing through her heels
okay go for it
okay interestingly some people who don't
like
frog pumps still like these frog reverse
hypers
including young grace okay
so that's the frog reverse we got two
more exercise left
get down in the quadruped
and this one face face
alex no face him like face the camera
okay you are going to
just get your knees up just a little
more right there okay so instead of just
coming out do a fire hydrant right now
okay what i want you to do is
sink as far to this side as you can and
then
come up and come as high as you can as
much
there come down sink boom
okay let's get five one
two higher good three yes
four last one five you feel that
see even young grace is feeling this one
okay and then the last exercise is the
rkc plank
so this is like a standing glue squeeze
it but in a in a plank position
she gets in a plank and then from here
squeeze the glutes as hard as she can
okay get a little higher
squeeze good you see this this is just
an
ugly movement you see this rounded back
the glutes are caved in you'll see the
hip dips
but this is working very well okay you
actually
feel this a lot more in your abs too not
only your rectus abdominis but your
internal external obliques
me and my buddy brad schoenfeld did a
study on this uh
god like must have been like eight years
ago or something but yeah your
abs end up working way harder so it's
not only a good glute exercise it's a
good abdominal exercise
and that concludes the intermediate
glute exercises
okay okay
now back for round three these are the
advanced glute exercises so
it's something to work your way up to if
you're a novice or an intermediate
not everyone can do these but if you are
advanced you used to go to the gym
you're used to piling on a lot of weight
you're going to be surprised
that a lot of these are are perfectly
suitable for you they're
you know they're you know people have
this misconception that
you know training from home is for
sissies or something like that and
you're going to see these are really
tough exercise you know i can't even do
some of them like i suck at pistol
squats
and cossack squats so
luckily i have grace here as she's
better at demonstrating a lot of these
so we're going to start out with the
dual elevated single leg hip thrust
so grace is going to put her arms out
put one leg up okay now she is going to
yep she's going to keep one leg up touch
the ground
boom come up this is a large range of
motion
yep okay then she switches
do okay these are brutal
okay and you'll fill these in the glutes
and the hamstrings
great okay all right
now we've got the partner hip thrust
okay so start
from the top all right
we've got walter here grace's boyfriend
okay
so she's gonna come to the top all right
get a little bit wider stance
walter you're going to stand in the
middle there nope facing this way
okay and you are going to sit down
there now put your
yep and then hold under legs now
she's gonna when you get down to the
bottom as she comes up it's gonna
push you forward you can keep your legs
can touch the ground a little bit it's
still hard okay
all right go for it come down nope so
keep your legs up
and then as you come up yes there okay
come down legs up
okay let's try and get ten reps two good
three good four
five see it's getting tough okay six
seven all right let's get three more
eight
two more come up high nine okay and
ten okay thank you walter much
appreciated okay
see she just got a good glute workout
walter what do you weigh
185 walter weighs 185 but it's just
it's just it's different from a barbell
like you can do
probably like 275 for 10. don't you
think barbell
you've done 315 for 10.
whoa but you can see there that it's
well
it's just awkward weight it's uh it's
different so she ended up getting a
good glute workout with her her
boyfriend now
um it's different like if walter
hip-trusted grace he'd need to do
30 reps or so but um
it's nice if you're oh especially like a
smaller woman like
woody weigh one 110. grace weighs 110
and she's hip testing her 185 pound
boyfriend me i weigh 250 so
yeah grace would hit like six reps with
me but anyway
that's the best way people always say
like you know when i
when i released these last year during
the quarantine
i got a lot of people that were like now
this is just ridiculous i don't care how
ridiculous something looks
i'm trying to get you to keep your
glutes or build your glutes from home
and this is the best thing you can do do
those partner hip dress all the time if
you can
so hopefully hopefully you have a
partner to do them with if not that's
fine there's
tons of other great glute exercises i'm
showing you now we are going to move on
to the high step up okay
so you can face this way grace is going
to put her foot
up on whole foot up there yep good
okay i'll make sure this doesn't move
okay puts her hands straight out come up
good okay now
the way we i usually start people out
by holding onto their hands like this
okay
and i say go fast boom yep
like that and then over time
then i would just say okay now do them
on your own
not that fast no yeah you won't be able
to do them that fast
but high step ups are amazing they're
such a good glute exercise the one thing
you wouldn't want to do is don't
shoot the hips up so much like show
where you like lean way forward and
shoot the hips up
yeah that's what i do and then that's
what i try and do with these so
make sure you keep a constant torso
angle while you do these
and again don't have your foot off the
the hair you'd be forced to push through
your toes
you want to always push through the
heels and don't spring up so much with
that bottom leg
okay now we've got the deficit
bulgarian split squat
okay you get a little stool
okay we might want to put this a little
closer
yep this goes a little closer than
normal
all right good now drop all the way down
to where your touch you almost touch
there yep
great okay this is the deficit
bulgarian split squat
great okay now
turn around this way face this way just
show a deficit reverse lunge
okay
good now the deficit reverse lunge it's
cool because you can
let's say you don't have this height
let's say you have this height
you can do them as well stand up here
okay drop down and
sink down into lunge well don't step
back that far
kind of step straight down let your knee
go forward yep there that's it
yep just like that okay
so you can have different heights of
deficits okay good
now we're gonna do a cossack squat
so stand wide white stance
okay now these are really tough
i suck at these thank god grace is here
so she is gonna come down onto this leg
and this leg will
it's like a side lunge but going really
deep this foot will turn up
okay go for it hands out good
come up okay next side
good okay these are brutal so the
cossack squat
is good for strength and glutes and
mobility too
you get a lot of stretch on those so
that's the cossack squat
now we're moving on to this single leg
box squad okay you would start off
high okay you're gonna
yep stand on one leg okay hands out
sit back stand up good
yeah so these are hard for me this would
be where i
where i'm at you know but
young grace could probably do them off
this let's see
let's see okay let's try
do a couple reps holding my hand okay
yep good
okay try it without me now
okay i think you can do it i think you
do it
go for it i mean that's almost a pistol
yep okay so she can do this thing like
box squat very low
now the next natural progression is the
pistol
but before we do regular pistols
off the ground i like the progression to
be standing on a
on something like this so stand up here
face this way
yep and then get close to the side now
you know back up just a little so your
whole foot is there and then
this way your leg doesn't have to come
straight out let it kind of dangle down
a little not that far no no no
it comes in front but it doesn't have to
be like way up here at the bottom you
know
okay go for it yep
up deeper can you go deeper yep
i got you okay deeper so this is what i
like to do
one more see how the leg can go down a
little bit
because now let's go here switch legs
okay now do the full pistol
oh okay full pistol okay she has a full
pistol see how this
i have trouble with this hip flexor is
weak it's really hard for me to hold
that leg up so
all right try one on your own
okay great all right so that's a pistol
squat
okay you all right
okay now we got one more kind of like
single leg knee dominant movement the
skater squat
and this is this looks like it'd be easy
but it's actually brutal
in fact i can't do a full skater squat
i've gotten to where i could but right
now
i can't because i weigh 250 and haven't
been doing them but
basically when when you start off with
these you might have to do partials
so grace is going to kind of lean
forward arms out
yep come down good i i so i do partials
can you do them touch the ground can you
touch the ground on them
the knee to the ground come up yeah
so that's a skater squat so show the
other leg show the weaker leg
okay just do a partial good
one more partial and then do one all the
way to the ground come on
you got this nice
okay so that's a skater squat okay
now we've got the single leg prisoner
back extending
so she's going to go here but it's one
leg
and this is very easy to hold i don't
even have to try here
it's so easy hands behind the back i can
just do this it's really easy
and then good he's going to come up
there okay
okay let's switch legs okay
two more good
great okay touch down i want to
make you flip again okay so that's the
single leg prisoner back extension
we've got two more exercises and these
are my two
favorite abduction movements for the
glutes for body weight exercises
and the first is this side lying hip
brace so
she's going to start kind of in a plank
like a sideline
almost like plank position but with her
legs bent like this
okay now she's going to
start with the legs bent and it's kind
of like
as you come up you don't just try to you
try to get maximum hip separation so
you're spreading your legs as far as
possible
but you also kind of drive the hips
forward a little bit okay
go for it boom so she comes
up and pushes forward like that okay
sinks back
pushes forward you want maximum hip
separation she's coming as high as
possible
boom okay these are hard i do three sets
of 12 on these
and they kick my butt and then finally
we've got these side lying
extra range side lying hip abduction
let's do them
off this and we'll put this stool here
for your other leg
so you are going to go this way
i'd obviously probably have like a
pillow let's put a pillow underneath you
okay go for it
okay this stool makes things so much
easier okay
so from here she's going to
turn the foot in she touches the ground
she comes up
now if she turned her foot this way she
could end up coming
way up to here you don't want to do that
okay stay this way
don't lean back like this stay in the
frontal plane
right here uh you want to feel this
right up here in the upper glute okay go
for it
yes and you can see it on grace see that
you can see it working
this is such a good upper glute exercise
all right
we do i start off people with sets of 20
when they get good they do sets of 30
then we'd switch to the other side and
repeat
and those are your advanced good
exercises
okay so as for what to do for your
actual workouts you're not going to do
every one of these exercises
what you're going to do is you're going
to pick one knee dominant movement
meaning
something that moves your knees and your
hips through a large range of motion so
the exercises like
squats lunges you know bulgarian split
squats step ups pistols skater squats
those are all examples of knee dominant
movements you're going to pick
one of those exercises and you're going
to perform
three to four sets then you're going to
pick a bridging movement
you know a hip thrust a
a bridge to different level different
feet elevations shoulder elevations one
leg two leg
frog pumps you're gonna pick one of
those exercises
and you'll do three to four sets and i
can't tell you the rep range because
that depends on you
some people might get 10 reps some
people might get 30 reps
and then finally you're going to pick an
abduction movement
and you're going to three to four sets
uh the abduction movements
are things like the side lying movements
you know the fire hydrants the
sideline hip raises um if you have bands
you can do
those band exercises there as well so
you're gonna pick an abduction moon
do three to four sets and then you could
finish
off with like a standing glute squeeze
or an rkc plank
those are good to do because you're just
squeezing your glutes as hard as
possible
but in this way you're only doing 9 to
12 sets
and you know they don't beat you up too
bad so you could almost train glutes
every day in this fashion but i would
recommend taking a couple days a week
off
so three to five days a week but the
thing is you got to utilize progressive
overload
you can't just do the same workout over
time you want to advance
in exercise difficulty which is obvious
because i broke those down into
different levels
you know the beginner and the
intermediate and advanced
but you can also increase in reps so say
you do
you know three sets of eight medium step
ups and then you get to where you can do
three sets of
15 medium step ups that's progression
then you move on to a high step
up you know and so you're doing three
sets of eight
high step ups and you get to where you
can do three sets of 15 high step ups
that's more progression so so over time
you want to move towards the advanced
column
and you want to be doing more and more
reps and of course if you do end up
getting dumbbells and ankle weights and
bands then you can add load that way
but until you do that you're going to
increase primarily in reps before you
move on to more advanced variations
so there you have it as you can see
there are some very advanced glute
exercises
you probably weren't expecting some of
those grace just left with her boyfriend
on her way out she's like i'm going to
be sore from that
so i hope you liked the video i hope you
learned a thing or two please go ahead
and hit like
please give it a thumbs up and make sure
you're subscribed to my channel because
i'm going to continue coming out with
great content on a regular basis
thanks for watching
[Music]
if you like what you saw in this video
and you want to train under my system
and principles
then i invite you to click on the link
below and subscribe to booty by brett
and join the thousands of other happy
members who are seeing amazing results
[Music]
yes